[
    {
        "question": "Which of the following best describes the process of asymmetric cryptography?",
        "options": [
            "It involves using the same key for both encryption and decryption.",
            "It uses different keys for the encryption and decryption process.",
            "It does not involve the use of any keys for the encryption or decryption process.",
            "It only involves the use of keys for decryption, not encryption."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "It uses different keys for the encryption and decryption process.",
        "id": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following algorithms is commonly used for secure data encryption?",
        "options": [
            "Rapid Algorithms",
            "ElGamal Algorithm",
            "Prime Algorithm",
            "Advanced Model Algorithm"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "ElGamal Algorithm",
        "id": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the process called that converts plain text into an unreadable series of characters in cryptography?",
        "options": [
            "Decryption",
            "Symmetric Encryption",
            "Asymmetric Encryption",
            "Encryption"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Encryption",
        "id": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "In the context of cryptography, what does the term 'symmetric encryption' refer to?",
        "options": [
            "It involves a process where two different keys - a public key for encryption and a private key for decryption - are used.",
            "It refers to a method where multiple keys are used to encode and decode the same message.",
            "It refers to a method where the same key is used for both encryption and decryption of a message.",
            "It involves a process where the encryption key is made publicly available while the decryption key remains private."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "It refers to a method where the same key is used for both encryption and decryption of a message.",
        "id": 4
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following cryptographic algorithms is considered to be a symmetric encryption algorithm?",
        "options": [
            "RSA",
            "Diffie-Hellman",
            "Advanced Encryption Standard (AES)",
            "Elliptic Curve Cryptography (ECC)"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Advanced Encryption Standard (AES)",
        "id": 5
    },
    {
        "question": "Which cryptographic algorithm is used by SSL and TLS for data protection during transmission?",
        "options": [
            "Data Encryption Standard (DES)",
            "Advanced Encryption Standard (AES)",
            "Rivest-Shamir-Adleman (RSA)",
            "Blowfish"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Rivest-Shamir-Adleman (RSA)",
        "id": 6
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is not a type of modern Cryptography?",
        "options": [
            "Symmetric-key Cryptography",
            "Asymmetric-key Cryptography",
            "Hash Functions",
            "Visible Cryptography"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Visible Cryptography",
        "id": 7
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following cryptographic systems uses a pair of keys for encryption and decryption?",
        "options": [
            "Symmetric Key Cryptography",
            "Asymmetric Key Cryptography",
            "Data Encryption Standard (DES)",
            "Identity-Based Cryptography"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Asymmetric Key Cryptography",
        "id": 8
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is known as a mathematical method for encrypting and decrypting information in cryptography?",
        "options": [
            "Hashing",
            "Symmetric Key Algorithm",
            "Asymmetric Key Algorithm",
            "Elliptic Curve Cryptography"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Asymmetric Key Algorithm",
        "id": 9
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is a symmetric-key algorithm utilized in cryptography?",
        "options": [
            "RSA",
            "SHA-256",
            "DES",
            "ECC"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "DES",
        "id": 10
    },
    {
        "question": "In the field of cryptography, which of the following refers to a method for protecting data in transit or storage that involves converting it into a coded version to prevent unauthorized access?",
        "options": [
            "Hash function",
            "Asymmetric cryptography",
            "Symmetric cryptography",
            "Encryption"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Encryption",
        "id": 11
    },
    {
        "question": "In the realm of cryptography, which of the following refers to a system where both parties use a single key for both encryption and decryption?",
        "options": [
            "Asymmetric encryption",
            "Symmetric encryption",
            "Hash function",
            "Public key infrastructure"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Symmetric encryption",
        "id": 12
    },
    {
        "question": "Which encryption algorithm is commonly used to secure sensitive data and is known for its block cipher design?",
        "options": [
            "RSA",
            "SHA-256",
            "AES",
            "Diffie-Hellman"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "AES",
        "id": 13
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the term used to describe the process of converting plaintext into ciphertext in Cryptography?",
        "options": [
            "Decryption",
            "Encryption",
            "Hashing",
            "Factoring"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Encryption",
        "id": 14
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is considered to be the most secure type of cryptography?",
        "options": [
            "Symmetric-key cryptography",
            "Quantum cryptography",
            "Hash function",
            "Caesar cipher"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Quantum cryptography",
        "id": 15
    },
    {
        "question": "What type of cryptographic technique allows two parties to generate a shared secret key for communication even if their conversation is overheard by a third party?",
        "options": [
            "Symmetric encryption",
            "Asymmetric encryption",
            "Diffie-Hellman key exchange",
            "Hash function"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Diffie-Hellman key exchange",
        "id": 16
    },
    {
        "question": "Which type of cryptography uses two mathematically linked keys, one for encryption and the other for decryption?",
        "options": [
            "Symmetric Cryptography",
            "Asymmetric Cryptography",
            "Quantum Cryptography",
            "Hash Functions"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Asymmetric Cryptography",
        "id": 17
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the primary purpose of a digital signature in cryptography?",
        "options": [
            "It encrypts the data to prevent unauthorized access.",
            "It verifies the identity of the party involved in a communication.",
            "It prevents the internet service provider from tracking one's internet usage.",
            "It accelerates the speed at which data is transmitted over the internet."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "It verifies the identity of the party involved in a communication.",
        "id": 18
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following algorithms is an example of asymmetric cryptography?",
        "options": [
            "Advanced Encryption Standard (AES)",
            "Triple Data Encryption Standard (3DES)",
            "RSA",
            "Blowfish"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "RSA",
        "id": 19
    },
    {
        "question": "What type of encryption is known for using two mathematically linked, but not identical keys?",
        "options": [
            "Symmetric Encryption",
            "Asymmetric Encryption",
            "Block Cipher",
            "Stream Cipher"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Asymmetric Encryption",
        "id": 20
    }
]